We were in a store and a guy in that store
told us to put our uniforms on.
"What the hell are you talking about?"
He says...
The USA is in a war with Japan.
We couldn't believe it.
Well. our country was attacked.
It's different.
It wasn't like Korea or Vietnam.
We was attacked.
And. you know. it was a feeling that...
Maybe. we're just dumb country people but
where I come from.
but a lot of us volunteered.
Who would like to volunteer
for the Tank Corps?
for the Air Force?
Who would like to volunteer
for the Navy or whatever?
And then. they said. "Who would like to
volunteer for the Airborne?"
Somebody says.
"What the hell's the Airborne?"
Nobody ever heard of it.
We came from a small. small town
and three fellas in that town were...
that were 4F
committed suicide
because they couldn't go.
A different time.
I did things. I didn't do 'em for medals.
I didn't do 'em for accolades.
I did 'em because...
it's what had to be done.
Guy says. "Would you
jump out of airplanes?
You know. you got all your army equipment
and you jump out of airplanes
to fight the enemy."
These guys. they said. "Go to hell."
Nobody put up their hands.
And then. I don't know
what it was brought it up.
But the guy giving the speech was saying.
"But you get paid $50 a month more."
So that made it 100 bucks.
[theme music playing]
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
[ominous music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[soldier shouting at a distance]
[soldier 1] Fox Company. we go in five.
[soldier 2] In the name of the Father
and the Son and the Holy...
[soldier 3] 1st platoon. draw small arms.
Need a hand. Lieutenant?
[Meehan] Easy Company!
Listen up! gather up around me.
Let's move it up. Come on. gentlemen.
Let's go!
Now the Channel coast is socked in
with rain and fog.
High winds on the drop zone.
-No jump tonight.
-[soldiers grumbling]
The invasion has been postponed.
-We're on a 24-hour stand-down.
-Son of a bitch.
[Meehan] Drill sergeants. take charge.
[soldier] 1st platoon squad leaders...
Well. this is quite a surprise.
Not particularly.
It so happens I rather expected it.
[Cary Grant] Well. I can't see
how you people can pass up
$80.000 for the cause.
[Laraine Day] For whose cause?
If you're so interested
in serving a cause.
why don't you join the Army?
[Cary Grant] Oh...
[indistinct dialog playing]
I think it's clearing up.
You think it's clearing up?
No.
I think it's clearing up.
How are your men?
They'll be fine.
5:00 in New York.
4:00 in Chicago.
-Happy hour. huh?
-[chuckles] Yeah. happy hour.
A couple of drinks.
maybe an early dinner before the theater.
A civilized place for civilized men.
[chuckles softly]
Should've been born earlier. Nix.
[scoffs] What. and give up all this?
We'll go to Chicago. I'll take you there.
Yeah.
We'll see.
Actually. you know who's from there?
Who? Oh. him.
712 days of that son of a bitch
and here we are.
[flies buzzing]
You people are at
the position of attention.
Private Perconte. have you
been blousing your trousers
over your boots like a paratrooper?
-No. sir.
-Then explain the creases at the bottom.
No excuse. sir.
Volunteering for the parachute infantry
is one thing. Perconte.
but you've got a long way
to prove that you belong here.
Your weekend pass is revoked.
-Name?
-Luz. George.
Dirt in the rear side aperture.
Pass revoked.
[gun cocking]
When did you sew on these chevrons.
Sergeant Lipton?
Yesterday. sir.
Long enough to notice this.
-Revoked.
-Sir.
-Name?
-Malarkey. Donald G.
Malarkey? Malarkey's slang
for bullshit. isn't it?
Yes. sir.
Rust on the butt plate
hinge spring. private bullshit.
Revoked.
[gun cocking]
-Name?
-Liebgott. Joseph D. sir.
Rusty bayonet. Liebgott.
You wanna kill Germans?
-Yes. sir.
-Not with this.
I wouldn't take this
rusty piece of shit to war.
and I will not take you to war
in your condition.
Now thanks to these men
and their infractions.
every man in the company
who had a weekend pass.
has lost it.
Change into your PT gear.
We're running Currahee.
[Winters] 2nd platoon fall out.
We have two minutes.
Fall out!
I ain't going up that hill.
Hey. Perconte. what are you thinking of.
Blousin' your pants?
Shut up. Martin. all right?
He gigged everybody.
Yeah? Well. you should know better.
-Don't give him no excuses.
-Excuses?
Why don't you come here.
look at these trousers.
get down and you tell me
if there's a crease on 'em?
All right. let's go. On the road
in PT formation. Let's move. move. move!
Perconte. let's go. Perconte.
Private White.
why are you not in your PT gear?
I asked you a question. Private.
[soldier] Oh. Easy Company.
Eh. while you're running. don't worry.
we'll take your dames
to the movies for you.
Yeah. good. they need some female company.
-[Sobel] Where do we run?
-[soldiers] Currahee.
-[Sobel] And what does "Currahee" mean?
-[soldiers] We stand alone.
[Sobel] How far up. how far down?
[soldiers] Three miles up.
three miles down.
-[Sobel] And what company is this?
-[soldiers] Easy Company.
-[Sobel] And what do we do?
-[soldiers] Stand alone.
-Ahh!
-Do not help that man!
Do not help that man. We do not stop.
You've got 13 minutes
to get to the top of this mountain
if you wanna serve in the paratroopers.
Hi-ho. Silver!
[intense music playing]
[Winters] Come on.
you can make it up there.
Come on now. Come on. Alley. let's go.
Come on. Guarnere. Christenson. come on.
I never thought I'd see the day.
Private Wynn.
We are coming on 23 minutes.
That may be good enough
for the rest of the 506.
but that is not good enough
for Easy Company.
[soldiers chanting]
We can make it. We can do this. come on.
Come on. Talbert. Come on.
Come on. Talbert. Come on. Go. Go.
I'm gonna say something.
To who?
Lieutenant Winters.
What is it?
Permission to speak. sir?
Permission granted.
Sir. we got nine companies. sir.
[Winters] That we do.
Well. how come we're the only company
marching every Friday night.
12 miles. full pack.
in the pitch dark?
Why do you think. Private Randleman?
Lieutenant Sobel hates us. sir.
Lieutenant Sobel does not
hate Easy Company. Private Randleman.
-He just hates you.
-[soldiers snicker]
Thank you. sir.
[soldiers laughing]
[soldier] He hates him back.
[Luz] He hates you. too. Muck.
Lieutenant Winters. I want canteens
out of belts with the caps unscrewed.
Easy Company. canteens out and open.
[Sobel] On my command. they will pour
the contents onto the ground.
On the C.O.'s order.
you will upend your canteen.
-[Sobel] Now. Lieutenant.
-[Winters] Pour 'em.
Who is this? Christenson.
Why is there no water in your canteen?
-You drank from your canteen. didn't you?
-Sir. I...
-Lieutenant Winters.
-Yes. sir.
Was this man ordered
to not drink from his canteen
-during the Friday night march?
-He was. sir.
Private Christenson.
you have disobeyed a direct order.
You will fill your canteen
and repeat all 12 miles
of the march immediately.
-Yes. sir.
-Fall out!
What in the name of God
are you doing with my company?
You're late and you allow troopers
to disobey direct orders?
No excuse. sir.
You're making me look bad. Lieutenant.
This is not Dog Company.
This is not Fox Company.
This... this is Easy Company.
And under my command.
this will be the first
and finest company in this regiment.
I want the names of six men.
their infractions
and your disciplinary recommendations
on my desk by 0130. Is that clear?
What infractions. sir?
Find some.
So what'd you do?
I picked six men
and gave 'em latrine duty.
The lucky six?
McDonald. Toye. Perconte.
Lipton. Muck and Guarnere.
-Why them? [sighs]
-It was their turn.
[laughs] Sobel's a genius.
I had a headmaster
just like him in prep school.
-I know the type.
-Lewis...
Michelangelo's a genius.
Beethoven's a genius.
You know a man in this company
who wouldn't double-time Currahee
with a full pack
just to piss in that guy's morning coffee?
-[Sobel] Let's go. let's go.
-[soldier] Go! 1.000. 2.000...
-Stand in the door.
-Go. 1.000. 2.000...
You just broke both your legs.
Private Gordon.
-Are you trying to get yourself killed?
-No. sir.
-Stand in the door.
-[whistle blowing]
[loud chattering]
Ahh!
Shit.
To the wall. to the wall. Over as a team.
Come on. get to the wall.
Jesus. what the hell is this?
That's pig guts. boy.
[groans]
God damn it!
[Sobel] Why are you here. Private Gordon?
-I wanna be in the airborne...
-I don't believe you.
Why are you here. Private Gordon?
I wanna be in the airborne. sir!
You have 50 minutes to the top and back
And I will be watching you.
What are you waiting for?
[panting]
[Sink] Easy Company has
the finest performance record
in the entire 2nd battalion.
I believe every bit of that
is thanks to you.
-Congratulations. Captain Sobel.
-Thank you. sir.
Isn't that Lieutenant Winters
leading Easy Company in PT?
-Yes. sir.
-He's a damn good man.
I was planning on giving him
a set of these today.
Why don't you do it?
He'd be proud to get 'em from you.
Pornography: contraband.
Non-regulation clothing: contraband.
This man had 200 prophylactic kits
in his footlocker.
How in the name of God was he gonna
have the strength to fight the war?
How is it private... Private Tipper
Has spare time for so much correspondence?
Captain. are personal letters
to be considered contraband?
[sniffing]
These men aren't paratroopers yet.
Lieutenant.
They have no personal property.
What is this? Anybody?
Uh. it's a can of peaches. sir.
Lieutenant Nixon thinks
this is a can of peaches.
That is incorrect. Lieutenant.
Your weekend pass is cancelled.
This is United States Army property
which was taken without authorization
from my mess facility.
and I will not tolerate thievery
in my unit.
Whose footlocker is this?
Private Parkes. sir.
Get rid of him.
All weekend passes are cancelled.
Officers included.
Carry on.
Lieutenant Winters.
Colonel Sink has seen fit to promote you.
As 1st lieutenant. you'll serve
as my executive officer.
-Congratulations.
-Thank you. sir.
And as a test of your
organizational skills
and command potential.
I am designating you
mess officer for 14 days.
Report to the mess kitchen at 0515 hours.
Company breakfast to be served at 0600.
Yes. sir.
Oh. and. Dick.
There's rain forecast tomorrow.
So the company will have a light afternoon
of lecture and classroom instruction.
I think a special meal
before their afternoon off
would be a welcome change of pace.
-Would you agree?
-Yes. sir.
I like spaghetti.
[soldiers cheering. laughing]
Hold on. more coming.
These guys are packing it away.
This stuff is orange.
Spaghetti ain't supposed to be orange.
This ain't spaghetti.
This is army noodles with ketchup.
If you ain't gotta eat it...
Oh. come on. gonorrhea.
as a fellow Italian.
You should know that calling
this crap spaghetti is a mortal sin.
-You want it or not...
-No. I'm eating here.
Get outta here.
[whistle blows]
Orders changed. Get up!
Lectures are cancelled.
Easy Company is running up Currahee.
Move. move!
Three miles up. three miles down.
Hi-ho. Silver!
Let's go. let's go.
[spits]
You're a washout. Private Hoobler!
You should pack up
both your ears and go home.
Looks like Gordon's done.
Aren't you. Gordon? You finished?
You do not deserve to get your wings.
Private Randleman. you look tired.
There's an ambulance waiting for you
at the bottom of the hill.
It can all be over right now.
No more pain. no more Currahee.
No more Captain Sobel.
♪ We pull upon the risers
We fall upon the grass ♪
♪ We never land upon our feet
We always hit our ass ♪
♪ Aye. aye. Christ Almighty
Who the hell are we? ♪
♪ Zim-zam. goddamn
We're Airborne infantry ♪
♪ We pull upon the risers
We fall upon the grass ♪
♪ We never land upon our feet
We always hit our ass ♪
♪ Hide tidee. Christ Almighty
Who the hell are we? ♪
♪ Zim-zam. goddamn
We're Airborne infantry ♪
[Sergeant] Do we feel like we're ready
to be army paratroopers?
-Yes. Sergeant!
-[Sergeant] I hope so.
This'll be the first of five exits
from a C47 aircraft
scheduled for today.
[Sergeant] Get ready!
Stand up. Hook up.
Upon successful completion
of your fifth and final jump.
you'll be certified Army paratroopers.
Check equipment!
Sound-off for equipment check!
-Nine okay.
-Eight okay.
-Seven okay.
-Six okay.
-Five okay.
-Four okay.
-Three okay.
-Two okay.
One okay.
[Sergeant] There'll be a lot of men
dropping from the sky today.
Hopefully. under deployed canopies.
Stand in the door!
I guarantee you're gonna
love it. Lieutenant.
Go. go!
Jumping from 1.000 feet AGL.
In sticks of 12 jumpers per aircraft.
All you have to do
is remember what you were taught.
And I guarantee you
gravity will take care of the rest.
[Sergeant] Go. go. go. go!
Go. go. go. go. go!
Go. go. go!
[grunts]
[Sobel] Damn it.
[Sergeant] And. gentlemen. rest assured
any refusals in the aircraft
or at the door...
and I guarantee you
you will be out of the Airborne.
-[soldier 1] Four okay.
-[soldier 2] Three okay.
-Two okay.
-One okay.
[Sergeant] Stand in the door.
Go!
[engine whirring]
[soldiers] One thousand. 2.000.
3.000. 4.000. 5.000. 6.000.
7.000. 8.000. 9.000!
[cheering]
Hi-ho. Silver!
Now. just think.
if you had any class or style like me.
somebody might mistake you for somebody.
You mean like your fucking sergeant?
I'm just kidding.
Congratulations. Martin.
[as Sobel] Corporal Toye. there will be
no leaning in my company.
Are those dusty jump wings?
How do you expect to slay the huns
with dust on your jump wings?
Luz. just give me a drink.
Hell of an idea. Joe. There you go.
[sniffs]
Three miles up. three miles down.
-[record scratches]
-[soldier] Ten-hut!
Well. at ease. paratroopers.
-Good evening. Easy Company.
-Evening. sir.
Now. parachute infantry
is a brand-new concept
In American military history.
But by God. the 506 is gonna
forge that brand-new concept into victory.
[soldiers] Yes. sir!
I want you to know that I'm damned proud
of each and every one of you.
Now. you deserve this party.
-Thank you. Sergeant Grant.
-Sir.
So I want you to have fun
and remember our motto...
-Currahee!
-[all] Currahee!
[all cheering]
[whistling]
[whispers] Petty.
Map. Come on.
Aw. Christ.
[muttering]
We're in the wrong position.
We're textbook position for ambush. sir.
I think we should sit tight.
let the enemy team come
into our killing zone.
They're right out there somewhere.
Let's just get 'em.
Sir. we have perfect cover here.
Lieutenant. deploy your troops.
2nd platoon. move out.
-What?
-Tactical column.
Captain. you've just been killed.
along with 95% of your company.
Your outfit?
Easy Company. 2nd battalion 506th.
[soldier] Leave three wounded men
on the ground
and report back to the assembly area.
God damn it.
You. you. you.
Well. what are you gonna do?
Nothing. just keep training the men.
Am I interrupting?
No. no.
Lieutenant Lewis Nixon.
Lieutenant Harry Welsh.
just in from the 82nd.
Congratulations on the promotion.
Oh. thanks. if you wanna call it that.
You'll learn him pretty quickly.
no flaws. no vices. no sense of humor.
Just like your chums up
at battalion staff.
What's up?
-I'm hearing a lot of rumblings.
-Sobel?
Just talking about that.
So he gets a little jumpy in the field?
Mm-hmm. he gets jumpy
and then you get killed.
[chuckles] That's nice.
Yeah. listen. if we discuss it. I think
it should just be amongst ourselves.
All right. absolutely.
-2nd platoon ready?
-Ready. sir.
Then get them in formation.
We're moving out.
Yes. sir.
-Shut up. Cobb.
-Eh. you got to admit it.
He's got no chance.
Either the Krauts will get him.
or one of us.
Who. Sobel?
He screwed up one maneuver.
Well. you know.
I'm always fumbling with grenades.
It would be easy if one
went off by accident. you know?
Well. now they must have
put him in charge for a reason.
Yeah. 'cause the Army
wouldn't make a mistake. right. shift?
-Going my way?
-Wherever the train takes me.
-Where do you suppose that might be?
-I haven't got a clue.
Yeah. come on. take a guess.
Atlantic. Pacific. Atlantic?
I'm not the intelligence officer.
Mm. Well. as such. I of course know.
But. uh. if I told you.
I'd have to kill you.
So don't tell me.
New York City. troop ship. England.
We're invading Europe. my friend.
Fortress Europa.
Since when do I drink?
If I thought you'd drink it.
I wouldn't offer it to you.
Nix?
What are you gonna do
when you get into combat?
Oh. I have every confidence
in my scrounging abilities.
And I have a case of Vat 69
hidden in your footlocker.
[laughs]
-Really?
-Oh. yeah.
Morning.
Mm. this could turn into a real nice trip.
[indistinct chatter]
[Sobel] "Dear sir or madam.
Soon your son will drop from the sky
to engage and defeat the enemy.
Your frequent letters
of love and encouragement
will arm him with a fighting heart.
With that he cannot fail.
but will win glory for himself.
make you proud of him
and his country ever grateful
for his service in its hour of need.
Signed Herbert M. Sobel.
Captain Commanding."
[foghorn blaring]
[Muck] Right now some lucky bastard's
headed for the South Pacific.
Oh. what I'd give. He's gonna get billeted
on some tropical island...
[soldier 1] Keep talking.
... sitting under a palm tree
with six naked native girls...
-[soldier 1] Yeah.
-...helping him cut up coconuts
so he can hand-feed 'em to the flamingos.
Flamingos are mean. They bite.
-So do the naked native girls.
-With any luck.
[Toye] Hey. guys.
I'm glad I'm going to Europe.
Hitler gets one of these
right across the windpipe.
Roosevelt changes
Thanksgiving to Joe Toye Day.
and pays me 10 grand a year
for the rest of my fucking life.
-[soldiers chuckle]
-What if we don't get to Europe?
What if they send us to North Africa?
My brother's in North Africa.
He says it's hot.
-Really. it's hot in Africa?
-Shut up.
The point is it don't matter where we go.
Once we get into combat.
the only person you can trust
is yourself and the fella next to you.
-Hey. as long as he's a paratrooper.
-Oh. yeah?
And what if that paratrooper
turns out to be Sobel?
If I'm next to Sobel in combat.
I'm moving on down the line.
hook up with some other officer
like Heyliger or Winters.
I like Winters. He's a good man.
But when the bullets start flying.
I don't know if I want a Quaker
doing my fighting for me.
[Muck] How do you know he's a Quaker?
-He ain't Catholic.
-[Guarnere] Neither's Sobel.
[scoffs] That prick's a son of Abraham.
-He's what?
-He's a Jew.
Oh. fuck.
-I'm a Jew.
-Congratulations.
Get your nose out of my face.
[soldiers clamoring]
What's all that about?
Gonorrhea called Sobel a Jew.
Liebgott took offense
'cause he's a Jew. too.
Fighting over Sobel... That's smart.
[indistinct shouting]
-Attack!
-Ahh!
No. you wanna kill him!
Parry right. parry left.
-Thrust! take cover.
-[all scream]
Okay. [clears throat] yesterday. we talked
about magnetic declination.
and the left add. right subtract rule.
Today we're gonna put it into practice.
There are two basic types
of fighting positions.
The first is the prepared position.
The advantages of a prepared position
are that it gives you
cover and concealment.
Commence fire!
We'll then maneuver
right in through these trees.
At the same time our 2nd platoon.
in this particular case. moves over here.
He's then gonna close with
and kill or capture that German.
[panting]
Sobel's late.
Why is there a fence here?
There should be no fence here.
-Tipper!
-Yes. sir.
Give me the map.
Perconte. Luz.
get the men. get 'em...
Take cover behind those trees.
-[Luz] You heard the word. Move out.
-[Perconte] Yes. sir. Up. up.
There should be no...
There should be no fence here.
Um... Ahem. [clears throat]
We... we could go over it. sir.
Really? That's not the point.
Where are the goddamn...
where the goddamn hell are we?
[cow moos]
-Perconte?
-Yeah.
-Sobel's lost again. right?
-Yeah. he's lost.
-Fucking Christ.
-Hey. Luz. Luz.
Hey. can you do Major Horton?
[as John Wayne] Does a wild bear crap
in the woods. son?
Shh. Maybe the good major
can goose this schmuck.
-Get us moving?
-No way...
-Oh yeah. yes.
-You gotta. you gotta.
-Come on.
-All right. just this once.
Shh. shh.
[clears throat]
356. 833.
-Isn't that the intersection?
-No. sir. it's here.
You're a full grid off.
[whispers] God damn it.
[Luz] Is there a problem. Captain Sobel?
Who said that? Who broke silence?
I think it's Major Horton. sir.
Major Horton?
What... what is he... Did he join us?
I think maybe he's moving between
the platoons. sir?
What is the goddamn holdup. Mr. Sobel?
[muffled laughter]
A fence. sir. Um. God...
A barbed wire fence.
Oh. that dog just ain't gonna hunt.
-[soldier snickering]
-Shut up. shh.
Now you cut that fence
and get this goddamn platoon
on the move!
Yes. sir!
[Sobel] where are my goddamn wire cutters?
Sir.
We have to move.
[Lipton] Sir. without Captain Sobel
and 1st platoon?
It's a "T" intersection. We improvise.
Double envelopment laid on a base of fire
to cut the road in all directions.
Hook right with 1st squad.
Tell Guarnere to move left with 2nd
and I'll be right up the middle with 3rd.
-Go.
-Yes. sir.
[humming]
Deary me.
[dog barking]
Bloody hell.
You've done it now. Yanks.
You've captured me.
[Sobel] Hi-ho. Silver!
Would that be the enemy?
As a matter of fact. yes.
Good work. 2nd platoon.
We took the objective.
[Strayer] Who was the idiot
who cut that man's fence?
-[Sobel] I was ordered to. sir.
-By whom?
Major Horton. sir.
-Major Horton?
-Yes. sir.
-Major Horton told you to do that?
Major Horton ordered you to cut the fence?
Yes. he did.
Major Horton is on leave in London.
Get those cows out of here.
[cow mooing]
Lieutenant Winters.
With Captain Sobel's compliments. sir.
Lieutenant.
Oh. for crying out loud.
Misspelled "court-martial."
No. sir. I do not understand.
Your orders to me
were to inspect the latrines
at 1000 hours.
From 0930 to 0955
I was censoring the enlisted men's mail
by order of Colonel Strayer.
At 1000 hours I followed
your orders to the minute.
I changed the time to 0945.
-No one told me. sir.
-I telephoned.
I'm quartered with a family
that has no telephone.
-And sent a runner.
-No runner found me. Captain.
Irregardless. when given
a task to perform by a ranking officer.
you should have delegated your task
of latrine inspection to another officer.
You failed to do so.
Were I to let such a failure of duty
by my own XO go unpunished.
what kind of message is that to the men?
I performed my duty as I was ordered. sir.
And I disagree.
So your options are quite simple.
Lieutenant.
Punishment for your offenses
will be denial
of a 48-hour pass for 60 days.
Stand before me at attention.
Or you may initiate a letter of appeal
and request a trial by court-martial.
You spend your weekends
on the base anyway. Dick.
Be a man. take the punishment.
May I borrow your pen. sir?
My endorsement. sir.
I request trial by court-martial.
We lost Winters to battalion mess.
-You're shitting me.
-No.
Strayer did it while they try
to figure out
the procedures for his court-martial.
Nixon better find a loophole
and get him out.
And if he don't?
Winters scrambles eggs
while the rest of us
make the big jump with Sobel.
Not me.
So we're going through with this. right?
We've gotta do something.
-Yeah.
-All right. Good.
But we'd all better be clear
of the consequences.
-I don't care about the consequences.
-Yeah.
We could be lined up
against a wall and shot.
Now. I'm ready to face that.
And every one of us had better be. too.
I will not follow that man into combat.
Me neither.
[whispers] All right.
Then let's do it.
[Guarnere] "I hereby
no longer
wish to serve
as a non-commissioned officer...
in Easy Company."
All right. boys. Good luck.
I ought to have you all shot!
This is nothing less than an act of mutiny
while we prepare for the goddamn invasion
of Europe.
-Sergeant Harris.
-Sir.
Turn in your stripes. collect your gear.
You are hereby transferred
out of my regiment.
-Sir.
-Get out.
-Sergeant Ranney.
-Sir.
You consider yourself lucky.
I'm only busting you to private.
All of you NCOs have disgraced
the 101st Airborne.
You can consider yourself lucky that
we are on the eve
of the largest action
in the history of warfare.
which leaves me no choice
but to spare your lives.
Now get out of my office
and get out of my sight.
Get.
[door opens]
[soldier] Keep 'em coming. that-a-boy.
That's it.
[Sobel] I can only speculate. sir.
Most of the men would...
would never do this.
But I believe just a few of the sergeants
may have felt their loyalty
lay more to the platoon
than to the company.
And these few sergeants convinced all
of the other NCOs in your company
to turn in their stripes?
As staff sergeants.
they have influence. sir.
But as I say. the rest are good men.
I know them. I can work with them.
This business with the Winters'
court-martial
has been an unpleasant distraction.
Indeed. indeed it has. sir.
-However...
-[liquid pouring]
Your command of Easy Company
has been exemplary.
Thank... thank you. sir.
In fact. except for the actions of a few
of your noncoms.
I believe you've fielded one of the finest
companies of soldiers I've ever seen.
Yes. sir.
Herbert. division has established
a parachute training school
at Chilton Foliat.
The idea is for non-infantry types
who were vital to the coming invasion.
such as doctors and chaplains.
to take jump training there.
Frankly. I can't think
of anyone more qualified
to command such a school than you are.
Sir?
I'm reassigning you to Chilton Foliat.
I'm losing Easy Company?
The war effort needs you elsewhere.
-Permission to speak. sir?
-Granted.
Is... Who... who will be replacing me?
Lieutenant Meehan from
Baker Company is senior.
Good luck at Chilton Foliat. Herbert.
Don't let us down now.
No. sir.
Carry on.
2nd platoon. listen up.
I want the 1st squad
and a-side tents right up there.
3rd squad. second row.
[indistinct chatter]
[imperceptible]
Holy shit.
No. it's all right. mate. We're Tommies.
-Not bleedin' boche.
-Is all this real?
Yeah. yeah.
Well. some of it's from the hermans
that somebody's tailors knocked up
for you lads so you can
get your mince pies
on some of this Jerry clobber.
if you know what I mean.
-Not really.
-Eh?
Hey. man. you got a Luger?
I'm dying to get my hands on a real Luger.
Yeah. go on then.
Quick butchers. yeah?
Boy. she sure is a doozy.
-Yeah. it's pukka. innit?
-What?
-Eh?
-Hey. Petty.
Hey. mate.
You're having a bath
if you think you're half-inching that.
Oh. yeah. Sorry.
-Hey. good luck.
-You too. mate.
What's up. Hoobs?
These men have been through the toughest
training the army has to offer
under the worst possible circumstances.
And they volunteered for it.
Christ. Dick. I was just
shooting craps with them.
-It's not like...
-You know why they volunteered?
So when things got really bad.
the man in the foxhole
next to them would be the best.
not some draftee
who's gonna get him killed.
Are you ticked because they like me?
Because I'm spending time
to get to know my soldiers?
I mean. come on. you've been
with these guys for. what. two years?
I've been here for six days.
You're gambling. Buck.
So what? Soldiers do that.
I don't deserve a reprimand for it.
What if you'd won?
-What?
-What if you'd won?
Never put yourself in a position
where you can take from these men.
-[Winters] Lieutenant Meehan?
-[Meehan] Enter.
On the last training jump.
I had a compass.
Close the flap.
-[Winters] Then we turn left.
-Yeah.
[Winters] Bearing 042. 12 minutes.
-Then another left?
-Yes.
-Yeah.
-Call it 358.
for ten and a half minutes.
Green light right over Ramsbury.
Ramsbury. Every single time.
Linear distance on the grid of about...
Okay. Ramsbury.
Upottery.
So... It's Normandy.
[Nixon] Sainte-Marie-du-Mont.
Causeway number 1. causeway number 2.
The ultimate field problem.
The estuary of the Douve River
divides two beachheads.
code-named Utah. here.
And Omaha. here.
Seaborne infantry will hit
these beaches in force
at a date and time to be specified.
H-hour. D-Day.
Airborne's objective. gentlemen.
is to take the town of Carentan...
[in American accent] or Carentan.
thus linking Utah and Omaha
into a single continuous beachhead.
[Meehan] ...thus linking Omaha and Utah
into one continuous beachhead.
Each trooper will learn
this operation by heart
and know his and every other
outfits' mission to the detail.
-Lieutenant Meehan?
-Yes. Dukeman.
Sir. are we dropping tonight?
When it's time for you to know.
we'll let you know.
In the meantime. study these sand tables.
maps and reconnaissance photos
until you can draw a map
of the area by memory.
Now. we will drop
behind this Atlantic wall
five hours before
the 4th infantry lands at Utah.
And between our assembly area
and the battalion's objective.
there is a German garrison right here
in this area. Sainte-Marie-du-Mont.
Easy Company will destroy that garrison.
Three-day supply of K-rations.
chocolate bars. Charms candy.
powdered coffee. sugar. and matches.
compass. bayonet. entrenching tool.
ammunition. gas mask.
musette bag with ammo. my webbing. my .45.
canteen. two cartons of smokes.
Hawkins mine. two grenades.
smoke grenade. gamma grenade.
TNT. this bullshit.
and a pair of nasty skivvies.
What's your point?
You know. this stuff weighs
as much as I do.
I've still got my chute. my reserve chute.
my Mae West. my M-1.
Where are you keeping your brass knuckles?
I could use some brass knuckles.
-Sergeant Martin!
-Hey. Vest. anything for me?
Nope. Sergeant Martin.
[indistinct chatter]
[Vest] Talbert.
Talbert.
White. White. here.
[Vest] Heavy. Condoms?
-I don't know. probably.
-What you got?
"Dear Floyd. give 'em hell."
It's from chief of the Kokomo
police department.
Right. [chuckles]
Whoa. you've gotta love cops.
[Lipton] All right. listen up. listen up.
If you did not sign your
GI life insurance policy.
you go on over and see Sergeant Evans
at the headquarters company tent.
You boys don't let your families
miss out on $10.000.
You hear that. Gerry?
-[Martin] Hey. Lip?
-Yeah. boy.
Has Guarnere said anything
to you about his brother?
-No.
-I got a problem.
My wife keeps up with things back home.
-Casualty lists and like that.
-Yeah?
-Guarnere's brother in Italy?
-Henry?
Killed in Monte Cassino.
-Well. I'm sure he doesn't know.
-Damn.
What do you think I should do?
If it were me. I'd tell him.
Couple of hours before we jump?
[sighs] I don't know.
Why they springing these things on us now?
It's just an extra 80 pounds
strapped to your leg.
Does anybody have any idea
how the hell this thing works?
Colonel Sink.
"Soldiers of the regiment...
[mimicking Sink] Tonight is the night
of nights.
[in normal voice] Today. as you read this.
you are en route
to the great adventure
for which you have trained
for over two years."
So that's why they gave us ice cream.
[Meehan] Easy Company. listen up!
Channel coast is socked in
with rain and fog.
No jump tonight.
-[soldier exclaims]
-[Meehan] The invasion has been postponed.
We're on a 24-hour stand-down.
Well. this is quite a surprise.
Not particularly.
It so happens I rather expected it.
[Cary Grant] Well. I can't see
how you people can pass up
$80.000 for the cause.
[Laraine Day] For whose cause?
If you're so interested
in serving a cause.
why don't you join the Army?
[woman] Next. please.
-[Cary Grant] 4-M.
-[Laraine Day] You look 1-A to me.
[Cary Grant] Hey. you don't look so bad
yourself. [laughs]
"Dearest Johnny."
[Laraine Day] Well.
should you be giving blood?
[Cary Grant] I woke up.
I got the wrong goddamn jacket.
-Shh.
-[Laraine Day] I was struck by lightning.
-[Cary Grant] Nobody dancing.
-[Laraine Day] It doesn't matter.
"Your pal. Bill Guarnere's brother..."
[Cary Grant] Remember this...
I didn't lie to you.
You were right and I was wrong.
[projector whirring]
[panting]
[somber music playing]
-[soldier] Good luck. lads.
-[Hoobler] See you. Tommy.
[soldier] Give Jerry one for me.
[soldiers] Try and get these leg
straps through.
Johnny?
Got something you might be looking for.
Took your jacket by mistake.
-I'm sorry.
-You read it?
Where the fuck is Monte Cassino?
I don't know. Italy somewhere.
Sorry about your brother. Bill.
I'm sorry for my ma.
He was. uh...
Let's get this over with.
Bill?
I'll meet up with you over there.
[Meehan] Gentlemen. Doc Roe
is handing these out for air sickness.
Orders are every man takes one now.
another 30 minutes in the air.
Lieutenant.
2nd platoon. listen up.
Good luck.
God bless you.
I'll see you in the assembly area.
[somber music playing]
If the wire constant is sensitive.
then I think all we should
have to deal with is...
Goddamn. Lieb.
That airsick pill is making me loopy.
[engine starts]
[engine whirring]
["The Mission Begins" playing]
[theme music playing]
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org